MIKE NEUDER

(719) 659 · 3861 ♦ michael.neuder@colorado.edu ♦ Personal Webpage

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A computer science and math undergraduate studying at University of Colorado at Boulder. I am fascinated by the use of machine learning, mathematical models, and computational science to predict and analyze the behavior of complex systems. I have a solid mathematical and computational background, as well as passion for learning and discovery that allows me to adapt quickly to a variety of research areas.

EDUCATION

University of Colorado, Boulder

Aug 2015-Present

B.A. in Computer Science

B.A. in Mathematics Minor in Statistics

Expected Graduation: May 2019

Deans List

Sewell Esteemed Scholars Award

Overall GPA: 3.8 - Computer Science GPA: 4.0

EXPERIENCE

Laboratory for Atmospheric and Space Physics / Lockheed Martin Software Engineering Intern

Feb 2017 - Aug 2017 *Boulder, CO*

- · Joint CU Boulder and Lockheed program in which CU students are trained at LASP to work at Lockheed when they receive security clearances.
- · Developed graphical applications using Python and C++ Qt Libraries.
- · Wrote interactive terminal applications using Perl and the Curses Module.
- · Developed graphical application testing suites using Eggplant Functional and SenseTalk.
- · Solved large scale problems using multi-threading and multi-processing techniques.

Lab of Dr. Michael Mozer

March 2017 - Present

Research Assistant

Boulder, CO

- · Developed neural networks using word processing and language analysis to predict reading behavior.
- · Synthesized data to train complex networks on a range of tasks.
- · Built classifiers and clustering analysis tools using to train models on unlabeled data.
- · Created several convolutional neural networks to replicate the Structural Similarity (SSIM) score of sets of images in order to embody a more accurate image quality evaluation metric.

Lab of Dr. Elizabeth Bradley

March 2017 - Present

 $Research\ Assistant$

Boulder, CO

- · Used information theoretic measures of weighted and non-weighted permutation entropy to analyze the information produced by the climate system through water isotopic data collected in ice cores.
- · Compared accumulation and weighted permutation entropy to evaluate the relationship between the two values.

- · Wrote code in Python to create plots and time series graphs, as well as organize the data and run entropy calculations.
- · Analyzed how adjusting parameters in the permutation entropy calculation impacted the correlation coefficient between permutation entropy and accumulation.

Spire Manufacturing Solutions

Manufacturing Intern

May 2014 - Aug 2014 Colorado Springs, CO

- · Operated CNC lathes and mills to manufacture metal components.
- · Inspected parts to verify measurements matched specifications prior to shipping the parts.
- · Repaired electric discharge machine and programmed machine to cut a custom part.

OTHER PROJECTS

Numerical Experiments Rubik's Cube Solver Python vs C++ she

Connect Four

Hack CU 2017

A series of numerical analysis experiments written in python.

Wrote a program in C++ that solves a cube from any scrambled position.

Created benchmark runtimes of programs in both languages.

Wrote a web application with Ruby on Rails to simulate a virtual girlfriend.

Created a graphical implementation of the game in PvQt.

Took part in hackathon and modeled the spread of infectious disease.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages (Experienced) Programming Languages (Proficient) Libraries **Tools**

Python, C++, Perl Ruby, R, Javascript, Matlab, bash numpy, scipy, matplotlib, tensorflow, scikit-learn, Qt git VCS, LaTeX, Linux, Jupyter Notebooks